各位亲朋好友  今天大家齐聚一堂
Friends. Family. We are gathered to celebrate here today
庆祝罗斯与艾蜜莉喜结良缘
...the joyous union of Ross and Emily.
罗斯  请跟我复述
Now, Ross, repeat after me.
我  罗斯
"I, Ross."
I, Ross.
娶你  艾蜜莉
"Take thee, Emily."
娶你  瑞秋
Take thee, Rachel.
艾蜜莉
Emily.
要继续吗
Shall I go on?
他说了瑞秋对不对
He said, "Rachel," right?
我要过去吗
Do you think I should go up there?
是的  请继续
Yes. Yes. Do go on.
我们最好重新来一遍
I think we'd better start again.
罗斯  请你跟着我说
Ross, repeat after me.
我  罗斯
"I, Ross."
I, Ross.
娶你  艾  蜜  莉
"Take thee, Emily."
娶你  艾蜜莉
Take thee, Emily.
否则还有谁
Like there'd be anybody else.
成为我的合法妻子  无论贫病
"As my lawfully wedded wife, in sickness and in health...
至死不渝
...till death parts us."
成为我的合法妻子  无论贫病
As my lawfully wedded wife, in sickness and in health...
至死不渝
...until death parts us.
我真的愿意  艾蜜莉
Really, I do. Emily.
请给我婚戒
Do you have the rings?
艾蜜莉  为罗斯戴上戒指
Emily, place this ring on Ross' finger...
象征你永远爱他
...as a symbol of your bond everlasting.
罗斯  为艾蜜莉
Ross, place this ring...
戴上戒指  代表你俩
...on Emily's hand as a symbol...
白头偕老
...of the love that encircles you forever.
我很乐意
Happy to.
罗斯与艾蜜莉已经宣誓
Ross and Emily have made their declarations...
我很荣幸宣布他们成为夫妻
...and it gives me great pleasure to declare them husband and wife.
你可以亲吻新娘了
You may kiss the bride.
这比他娶同性恋那次更糟糕
This is worse than when he married the lesbian.
保持微笑
Just keep smiling.
好的
Okay.
进行得真顺利
Well, that went well.
他没开枪杀死她就不错了
It could've been worse. He could've shot her.
刚刚真好笑  不是吗
That was pretty funny, wasn't it?
你搞砸了所有事情  我丢死人了
You spoiled everything! It's a nightmare!
我的亲朋好友都在场  以后我怎么见人
My friends and family are out there! How can I face them?
你怎么能这样对我
How can you do this to me?!
无论罗斯和艾蜜莉结果如何
No matter what happens with Ross and Emily...
我们都吃得到蛋糕吧
...we still get cake, right?
没关系
That's all right.
亲爱的  你慢慢来  我在外面等你
You take your time sweetie, I'll be right out here.
她要补妆
She's just fixing her makeup.
我恨你
I hate you!
我也爱你
And I love you!
罗斯  这可不是说错名字的好时候啊
Boy, a bad time to say the wrong name, huh Ross?
你说得对  谢了  老爸
That's true. Thanks, Dad.
大家应该跳舞啊
People should be dancing.
这是婚宴啊  跳吧
This is a party! Come on!
乔伊  跳舞啊
Joey! Dance!
你好  华森公馆
Yes, Waltham Interiors.
你好  我是罗斯·盖勒的私人医生费兰吉
Hello, this is Ross Geller's personal physician, Dr. Filangie.
谁
Who?
我发现罗斯忘了吃精神药物
I discovered that Ross forgot to take his brain medicine.
如果不吃药  在罗斯的脑中
Without it, in the brain of Ross...
女人的名字会互相调换
...women's names are interchangeable.
这完全不能怪他
Through no fault of his own.
天哪  菲比
Oh, my God! Phoebe.
我不是菲比  是费兰吉医生
No, not Phoebe. Dr. Filangie.
原来你也是精神有问题
Oh, no! You have it too!
希望你别误会
I hope you don't take this the wrong way...
我知道我们今晚约了要见面
...but I know we had plans to meet up tonight, and...
我只是担心这样会影响我们的友谊
I'm just kinda worried about what it might do to our friendship.
我明白
I know.
-我们怎么这么不小心  -还不小心了七次
- How could we have let this happen? - Seven times!
你知道的  我们人在国外
You know, look. We were away.
又是浪漫的异乡
In a foreign, romantic country.
都怪伦敦不好
I blame London.
坏伦敦
Bad London!
所以  你看
So look...
我们还在伦敦时就可以继续  对吗
...while we're still in London, we can keep doing it, right?
看来我们别无选择
Well, I don't see that we have a choice.
但是我们回去后就得停止
But when we're back home, we don't do it.
只有这里例外
Only here.
我看到楼下有个酒窖
You know, I saw a wine cellar downstairs.
-我两分钟后下去找你  -好的
- I'll meet you there in two minutes. - Okay.
莫妮卡  我有事情要问你
Mon? Honey, I gotta ask you something.
现在吗
Now?
罗斯刚刚说了我的名字
Ross said my name up there.
我不能假装没听到吧
Come on, I can't just pretend it didn't happen, can I?
我不知道
I don't know.
莫妮卡  我该怎么办
Monica, what should I do?
不要出错就行
Just do the right thing.
什么
What?
听天由命  努力争取  不要死心眼
Tow the line! Thread the needle! Think outside the box!
听我说
Wait, listen,
我想直接去问罗斯他是什么意思
I think I'm gonna talk to Ross about what he thinks it meant.
等等  瑞秋  不要
Wait! Rachel, no.
他结婚了
He's married.
结婚了
Married.
要是你还不懂  我也没办法
If you don't realize that, I can't help you.
对  你说得对
Okay. You're right.
你说得对  你帮不了我
You're right. You can't help me.
杰克  这是我们的错吗
Jack, is it all our fault?
-我们是不合格的家长吗  -是的
- Were we bad parents? - Yes.
是吗  什么人会让客人站着吃牛排
Oh yeah? Who serves steak when there's no place to sit?
叫人家怎么吃
I mean how are you supposed to eat this?
还好吗
Hey, what's up?
你去哪里了  不是约在酒窖见吗
Where were you? We were supposed to meet at the wine cellar.
-算了  没戏了  -为什么
- Forget it. That's off. - Why?
下一次的酒窖参观
The next tour of the wine cellar...
将在两分钟后举行
...will plan in two in-in minutes.
乔伊  你搞什么
Joey, what are you doing?
你答应菲比  等她生完才吃肉
You promised Phoebe you won't eat meat till she has the babies.
我想既然我们在国外就不算
I figure we're in another country, so it doesn't count.
-那倒是  -他说得太有道理了
- That's true. - The men's got a point.
嗨
Oh, hi.
Hi.
抱歉  事情竟然出了状况
I'm sorry things aren't working out so well.
不
No...
的确不太妙  不过会解决的
It could be better. It'll be okay, right?
当然了  她不会放在心上的
Oh, yeah! Of course. She's gonna get over this, you know.
你脱口说出我的名字又如何
I mean, so you said my name.
不过是因为你刚好看到我
You know you just said it because you saw me there.
如果你看到的是马戏团小丑  你就会说
If you'd seen a circus freak, you would've said:
我娶你  马戏团小丑
"I take thee, circus Freak."
根本没有别的意思  只是无心之过
It didn't mean anything. It's a mistake.
没有别的意思  对吧
It didn't mean anything. Right?
当然没有别的意思了
Oh, no! Of course it didn't mean anything. I mean...
但是我明白艾蜜莉为何误会
I can understand why Emily would think it meant something...
因为是你的名字
You know... because it was you.
但是没别的意思  真的没有
But it absolutely didn't. It didn't! It didn't!
罗斯  乐队正在等你跟艾蜜莉开舞
Ross, the band's ready outside for your first dance with Emily.
原来乐队准备好了
Oh! The band's ready!
我们最好听乐队的话
We've got to do what the band says.
我才不在乎什么傻瓜乐队呢
I don't care about the stupid band!
你口水喷到我了
You spit on me, man!
对不起
I'm sorry.
艾蜜莉也进去太久了吧
Emily is taking kind of a long time.
我结婚时也躲在厕所不出来
You know when I locked myself in the bathroom at my wedding...
那是因为我要撬开窗户
...because I was trying to pop the window out of the frame.
我一心想要逃出去
Get the hell out of there. You know?
艾蜜莉  艾蜜莉
Emily! Emily!
我要进去了
I'm coming in!
你看  同一招
Oh, look at that. Same thing.
如果我中途大喊
Listen, in the middle of everything,
"好耶"  你就当作没听到
if I scream, "Yippee!" just ignore me.
-天啊  瑞秋  -你好  瑞秋
- Oh, my God! Rachel! - Oh, hello, Rachel.
罗斯说的是我的名字
Ross said my name.
知道吗  我的名字
Okay? My name!
他在婚礼上说出我的名字
Ross said my name up there.
很显然表示他还爱着我
That obviously means he still loves me!
不信就算了  我绝对没误会
Okay, don't believe me. I know I'm right.
你们要不要下楼喝一杯
Do you guys want to go downstairs and get a drink?
好啊
Yes, we do.
不过我们要先换衣服
But we have to change first.
对  我想换衣服
Yes, I want to change.
你先下去占位子吧
Why don't you go down get us a table.
-我们五分钟就下去  -十五分钟
- We'll be down like five minutes. - Fifteen minutes.
好的
Okay.
喂  菲比啊  是菲比
Hello. Oh, Pheebs! It's Phoebe!
-是吗  -太好了
- Oh, hey, hey. - Oh, great.
怎么样
So, what happened?
罗斯说出了我的名字
Well, Ross said my name.
我知道  不过他是无心的
I know. But I don't think that means anything.
菲比  这样吧
Okay, Phoebe, you know what?
我们冷静客观地想想看
Let's look at this objectively, all right.
高一那年
Ninth grade, right?
他就疯狂迷上了我
The obsession starts, all right?
高一暑假
Summer after ninth grade,
他头一次看我穿两件式泳衣
he sees me in a two-piece for the first time.
更是不可自拔爱上我
His obsession begins to grow, right?
去我房间换衣服好了
Listen, why don't we go change in my room?
可是我的衣服在...
My clothes are...
你看起来真是...
Wow, you look...
-没时间废话了  -好的
- No time for that. - Okay.
老兄  让我进去  我有女伴
Hey, dude! Let me in! I got a girl out here!
我也有
I got a girl in here!
才怪  我看到你跟莫妮卡进去了
No, you don't. I just saw you go in there with Monica.
我们在里面聊天
Well, we're hanging out in here.
你说我们谁有机会上床
Look, which one of us is gonna be having sex in there, me or you?
看来我只能说是你了
Well, I suppose I would have to say you.
-我们要是想看电影呢  -是的
- What if we're watching a movie in here? - Which we are!
我们都付费了
And we aleady paid for it.
正在看《我的巨人》
It's My Giant.
《我的巨人》
My Giant?
我爱死那部电影了
I love that movie!
你确定这样好吗
You really think this is okay?
反正罗斯跟艾蜜莉也用不到
Well, Ross and Emily aren't going to use it.
这里好漂亮
Oh, it's so beautiful!
可是我总觉得不太妥当
I don't feel right about this.
莫妮卡听我说
Oh Mon-Mon-Mon-Mon-look
这是蜜月套房
This is the honeymoon suite.
房间期待着性爱
The room expects sex.
如果没有  这间房一定很失望
The room would be disappointed if it didn't get sex.
在其它蜜月套房面前抬不起头
All the other honeymoon suites would think it was a loser.
-好吧  -好的
- Okay. - Okay.
艾蜜莉
Emily!
没有  没看到
Nope! Not under here!
-你还没找到她吗  -我到处都找遍了
- You didn't find her? - No, I've looked everywhere.
你一定漏掉了什么地方  否则早就找到了
You couldn't have looked everywhere, or else you would've found her.
-你应该继续找  -大概再找个三十分钟
- I think you should keep look! - Yeah! For about 30 minutes?
或是四十五分钟
Or 45?
四十五分钟可以找到两次了
Wow! In 45 minutes, you could find her twice.
不了  说不定
No, for all I know,
她想找我也找不到  因为我跑来跑去的
she's trying to find me but couldn't, because I kept moving around.
从现在开始我不动了
From now on, I'm staying in one place.
我就待在这里
Right here.
-时间晚了  -我们要走了
- Well it's getting late. - We're going to go.
其实吧
Actually,
陪陪我如何
do you guys mind staying here for a while?
可是我们明天一早就要搭机回纽约
You know, we've got to get up early and catch that plane to New York.
是啊  很大的飞机
Yeah, it's a very large plane.
那就算了
That's cool.
不过我们还是陪你一会
But we'll stay here with you.
谢了  两位
Thanks, guys!
我很感激  但是你也不用摸我屁股啊
I really appreciate this, but you don't need to rub my butt.
我们一小时后就要回纽约了
We have to leave for New York in an hour.
我知道  我一直在看那扇门
I know. I've been looking at those doors.
隔音效果似乎很好  你觉得呢
They look pretty soundproof, don't you think?
不行  你疯了
We can't do that. That's insane.
第一  他可能醒来  第二
I mean, A, he could wake up. And B, you know...
管他呢
...let's go for it.
艾蜜莉  艾蜜莉  艾蜜莉
Emily, Emily, Emily!
艾蜜莉
Emily!
不是
Nope.
不用找她了  她没来
You can forget about Emily, she's not with us.
我们来拿她的东西
We've come for her things.
她在哪里
Where is she?
她躲起来了  因为她很丢脸
She's in hiding. She's utterly humiliated.
这辈子都不想再见到你
She doesn't want to see you ever again.
很遗憾你们两个闹成这样  兔崽子
We're very sad that it didn't work out between you and Emily, monkey.
不过你实在是秀色可餐
But I think you're absolutely delicious!
抱歉  我人还站在这里呢
Excuse me, I'm standing right here.
是啊
Oh, yes.
阴魂不散
There you are.
大家动作快  外面还有一车
You guys hurry up! Get some! There's a whole cart outside.
再见了  盖勒
Goodbye, Geller.
等一下  别走
Now, hold on. Hold on.
听我说  令媛跟我
Look, look. Your daughter and I
今晚应该去度蜜月
are supposed to leave tonight for our honeymoon.
请你转告她  我会去机场
You tell her I'm gonna be at that airport,
我希望她也会去
and I hope she will be there too.
我说了瑞秋的名字  但这只是无心之过
I said Rachel's name, but it didn't mean anything, okay?
她不过是我的朋友  仅此而已
She's just a friend. That's all!
请转告艾蜜莉  我爱她
Just tell Emily I love her and...
我只想跟她共度余生
...I can't imagine spending my life with anyone else.
求你了  请保证一定会转告她
Please, promise me that you'll tell her that.
好吧  我会告诉她
All right, I'll tell her.
走吧  臭婆娘
Come on, bugger face!
打电话给我
Call me.
你也一天到晚待在厕所
You spend your half life in the bathroom.
怎么就不会从窗户滚蛋
Why do you never go out the bloody window?
或许我们不再上床才对
You know, maybe it's best we never got to do it again.
否则那晚就不特别了
Yeah, it kind of makes that one night special.
理论上讲我们还在国际海域上
You know technically, we still are over international waters.
我去洗手间
I'm going to the bathroom.
-待会来找我  -好的
- Maybe I'll see you there in a bit? - Okay.
我可以问个问题吗
Can I ask you something?
不行
No.
我昨晚跟费丽西蒂一起看《我的巨人》
Felicity and I we were watched My Giant-
我心想
And I was thinking:
自己永远不可能演得跟那个巨人一样棒
"I'll never gonna be as good an actor as that giant."
我执着于当演员是不是浪费时间呢
Do you think I'm wasting my life with this acting thing?
不
No.
那个巨人大概比我小五岁
I mean, the giant's like five years younger than me.
我有办法跟他一样优秀吗
You know? You think I'll ever get there?
是
Yes.
-谢了  -不客气
- Thanks, man. - Okay, man.
但是他比我高好多啊
But what about how much taller he is than me?
我现在已经不可能再长高了
I mean, there's no way I can make myself taller now, you know.
以后科学怎么发展又有谁知道呢
Who knows what science will come up with in the future...
钱德勒
...but Chandler
如果我死时  只是一个普通身高的小人物呢
what if I die an unsuccessful, regular-size man?
莫妮卡  你上厕所上了半个小时
Hi, Monica, you've been in the bathroom for like a half-hour.
我知道
I know!
你也吃了牛肉啊
Had the beef tips, huh?
你吃过肉了
You ate meat!
你(们)上床了
You had sex!
我们才没有
No, we didn't.
我知道你没有  我说的是莫妮卡
I know you didn't. I was talking about Monica.
菲比  我才没跟人上床呢
Phoebe, I did not have sex.
怀孕害我灵力不强了
This pregnancy is throwing me all off.
-我要去跟阿鸡阿鸭打招呼  -我也去
- I'm gonna say hi to the chick and duck. - Me too!
你何必去
Why would you need to say hi?
你已经喂了它们四天了
You've been feeding them for four days.
没错  我回家好了
Oh, right. Maybe I'll just go home.
只剩下我们两个了
We certainly are alone.
是的  幸好我们说好回纽约就不行
Yes. Good thing we have that "not New York" rule.
没错
Right.
你看  既然说到这个
Listen, since we're on that subject...
我想告诉你
...I just wanted to tell you that...
当时我在伦敦心情很不好
I was going through a really hard time in London...
因为我哥结婚
...what with my brother getting married
-别人还把我认作是他妈  -没错
- and that guy thinking I was Ross' mother. - Right.
不过  无论如何
Well, anyway, I just...
那晚对我来说意义非凡  我要谢谢你
That night meant a lot to me. I guess I'm just trying to say thanks.
那晚对我来说也是意义非凡
You know, that night meant a lot to me too.
并不是因为我也心情不好什么的
It wasn't because I was in a bad place or anything.
我觉得很重要是因为  你太正点了
It just meant a lot to me 'cause, you're really hot!
这样说可以吗
Is that okay?
没关系
That's okay.
而且我也很帅
And I'm cute too?
而且你也很帅
And you're cute too!
谢谢
Thank you.
-我要去整理行李了  -好的
- All right, I gotta go unpack. - Okay.
拜
Bye.
我时差还没调回来  这样可以算吗
I'm still on London time. Does that count?
-当然算  -太好了
- Oh, that counts! - Oh, good!
瑞秋  瑞秋
Rach, Rach.
嗨
Hi.
你怎么会在这里
What are you doing here?
我等候补机位回纽约  已经等了几小时了
I've been on standby for a flight home for hours.
你还没等到艾蜜莉
So no sign of Emily?
还没
Not yet.
那个
So...
你是什么时候的飞机
What time do you suppose to leave?
前住雅典的1066航班  最后一次呼叫登机
This is the last call for flight 1066 to Athens-
最后一次呼叫登机
The last call-
我想就快了
Pretty soon, I guess.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
我不明白
I just, I don't understand.
她怎么可以这样
How could she do this?
我是不是白痴  竟然以为她会来
Am I like a complete idiot for thinking she'd actually show up?
不
No.
你不是白痴  罗斯
You're not an idiot, Ross.
你只是爱得无可救药
You're a guy very much in love.
那还不是一样
Same difference.
搭乘1066航班前住雅典的旅客请登机
All passengers for flight 1066 to Athens should now be onboard-
听到了
I get it!
没希望了
Well, that's that.
错  知道吗
No, you know what?
我觉得你应该去
I think you should go.
-什么  -是的  我觉得你应该自己去
- What? - Yeah. I do. I think you should go by yourself,
在遥远的地方
get some distance,
想个清楚  我认为会很有帮助
clear your head. I think it'd be really good.
我不知道
I don't know.
去吧  罗斯  这对你一定有帮助
Come on. Ross, I think it would be really good for you.
我可以去
I could, yeah, I can do that.
我简直无法相信她
I can't, I can't even believe her!
知道吗  我决定去了
No, y'know what, I am, I am gonna go!
-很好  -有何不可呢
- Good. - Why not?
-对不对  -对
- Right? - Right.
谢了
Thanks.
我们纽约见了
Okay, I'll see you back at home.
希望我搭得上飞机
If I ever get a flight out of here.
怎么了  怎么了
What? Wait, what?
不如你也一起来
Why don't you come?
反正我有两张机票
I mean, I have two tickets. Why not?
不太好吧  罗斯  真的吗
Well, I don't know, Ross. Really?
是啊  一定很好玩  你可以...
Yeah. It'd be great. I mean, you can...
你可以躺在海滩上
You can lay on the beach...
我可以哭诉婚姻失败
...and I can cry over my failed marriage.
你看我多幽默啊
You see how I make jokes?
真的
Really. I mean...
我需要有朋友陪我
I could use a friend.
好吧  无妨
Oh, wow. Okay, maybe.
-我可以陪你去  -好的
- Yes, I can do that! - Okay.
-太好了  -走吧
- Cool. - All right.
我们去希腊
Okay, we're going to Greece.
我忘了拿外套
I forgot my jacket!
-你叫他们等一下  -好的
- Well, you tell them to wait. - Okay.
等一下
Wait! Wait!
艾蜜莉
Emily.
别误会  不是的
Oh no-no-no! Oh-no!
别走  别走
No! No!
艾蜜莉
Emily.
我要杯梅洛红酒
Yes, I'll have a glass of Merlot...
这位要气泡酒
...and he'll have a white wine spritzer.
瞧啊  机场在动
Hey, look at that, the airport's moving.
飞机在动吗
Are we moving?
飞机在动吗  为什么飞机会动
Are we moving? Why are we moving?
暂停下
Hey, time-out,
机长知道飞机在动吗
umm, yeah, does the captain know that we're moving?
老天爷啊
Oh, my gosh!